irregular verbs 不規則動詞 第二類 第二の形と第三の形とが同じなもの
bend bent bent lend lent lent send sent sent dwell dwelt dwelt
bind bound bound find found found grind ground ground wind wound wound
bring brought brought build built built buy bought bought catch caught caught
cling clung clung dig dug dug keep kept kept sleep slept slept
feed fed fed feel felt felt leave left left mean meant meant meet met met
lead led led read read read fight fought fought get got got hang hung hung
have had had hear heard heard hide hid hid hold held held lose lost lost make made made
say said said seek sought sought sell sold sold shine shone shone shoot shot shot
sit sat sat stand stood stood 第三類 第二の形のみ変化するもの
come came come become became become run ran run
第四類 規則的にもまた不規則にも働くもの その一 burn burnt burnt clothes clad clad dream dream dream
learn learnt learnt light lit lit wake woke woke
同じくその二hew hewed hewn mow mowed mown show showed shown swell swelled swollen
第五類 第一第二第三の三つの形が同じなもの 第一の形のみを挙げます
birth cast cost cut hit hurt let put set shed shut spread